

Alexander Popov

Male, 31 year, born on 23 May 1988

+7-903-473-14-60 b059ae@gmail.com skype: b059ae https://bitbucket.org/b059ae/ https://github.com/b059ae

Profile

Full Stack Web Developer with 10+ years experience in creating web-applications and configuring servers. Agile Kanban/Scrum Methodologies.

Working with PHP frameworks (Laravel, Yii), SQL (MySQL, PostgreSQL), MongoDB, JQuery, Bootstrap, Flexbox, HTML5, Git, Docker. Learning React.

Experience

WEB DEVELOPER, FINBRIDGE - 2019 - PRESENT

https://finbridge.io

Configured server environment: production, testing and development with Docker Laradock. Created landing page, user cabinet, administration backend. Integrated with SmsDelivery, G Suite, Bitrix24.

Used technologies and frameworks: PHP 7.3, Laravel, MariaDB, Flexbox, Tars, Gulp, Git, Docker, Laradock, Supervisord, Nginx, Certbot.

SENIOR WEB DEVELOPER, CREDIT BUREAU MICROFINANCE - 2016 - 2019

Created API and Web UI for storing, managing and selling credit data. 4 new types of credit reports and scores were created. Storing about 18 millions credit stories, 35k unique visitors per day.

Applications based on PHP Yii2 framework, MySQL Percona, MongoDB, JQuery, Bootstrap, Git, Nginx. Integrated with Gosuslugi, AmoCRM, 3 Credits Bureau: Equifax, TransUnion (NBKI), Russian Standard Credit Bureau. Built encrypting connection with GOST crypto library via Stunnel. Created scoring reports based on FICO. SMS and Email triggers, Call tracking, Google Analytics, A/B testing. Full-automated backup with Bacula and production deployment.

WEB DEVELOPER, SITE-CONTROL - 2014 - 2016

http://site-control.ru

Created standalone web application for automatic get, manage and view any site's data. 30+ crawlers and API integrations were created: Google, Yandex, Yahoo, Bing, Mail, Facebook, PayPal etc. 35000+ active users and installs of application.

Used technologies and frameworks: PHP, Yii, MySQL, IonCube, Git, Bootstrap, JQuery. Application includes web-installer and updater to last release.

Education

Southern Federal University (former Rostov State University) – Master's degree, Information Technology, 2005 - 2010.

Additional Courses

Elisdn, Yii2 master-class, 2017 Elisdn, RabbitMQ master-class, 2018

learn.javascript.ru, React.JS, 2018 Elisdn, Laravel master-class, 2019